<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Medieval Blog &#8211; MEDIEVAL ART HISTORY</title>
	<atom:link href="https://medievalarthistory.org/category/medieval-blog/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://medievalarthistory.org</link>
	<description>with the AP Art History Course</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 19:15:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">194999971</site>	<item>
		<title>Jewish Marriage Rings</title>
		<link>https://medievalarthistory.org/jewish-marrage-rings/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Medieval Art History]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 19:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Medieval Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://medievalarthistory.org/?p=1146</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jewish Marriage Rings Jewish marriage-rings throughout early history, were known for both intricacy and ornamentation. Traditionally, these were made of &#8230; <span class="more-button"><a href="https://medievalarthistory.org/jewish-marrage-rings/" class="more-link">Continue Reading<span class="screen-reader-text">Jewish Marriage Rings</span></a></span>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2><strong>Jewish Marriage Rings</strong></h2>
<p>Jewish marriage-rings throughout early history, were known for both intricacy and ornamentation. Traditionally, these were made of gold, a metal that does not tarnish. It is said this tradition ensures the marriage will be lasting and beautiful.</p>
<p>The band would have been placed on the right hand of the index finger at some point during the ceremony. Today it still is, except many new brides choose to later wear it on the left or right ring finger.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1151" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1151" style="width: 990px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-1151" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/1469228001.jpg?resize=990%2C705&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="990" height="705" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/1469228001.jpg?resize=1024%2C729&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/1469228001.jpg?resize=300%2C214&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/1469228001.jpg?resize=768%2C547&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/1469228001.jpg?resize=1536%2C1094&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/1469228001.jpg?w=1980&amp;ssl=1 1980w" sizes="(max-width: 990px) 100vw, 990px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1151" class="wp-caption-text">© The Trustees of the British Museum</figcaption></figure>
<h5>The Waddesdon Bequest</h5>
<p>This Jewish marriage-ring is part of the Waddesdon Bequest, consisting of medieval and Renaissance pieces, left to the British Museum, in London, England, by Baron Ferdinand Rothchild, in 1898.  Historians initially agreed that this ring was crafted during the 16<sup>th</sup> century, yet today place its creation between 1700-1898. There is speculation as to where it was made and Venice, Germany or Eastern Europe were suggested as possibilities.</p>
<h5><strong>The Details</strong></h5>
<p>This ring is exceptionally beautiful. The borders along both the top and bottom are made of twisted golden cables. There are five protruding, round bosses of filigree or delicate wire. The term filagree comes from the word “filum” meaning thread and “granum” meaning grain or small beads.</p>
<p>Each boss is highly decorated with a six petaled flower in the center. The enamel flowers are either a combination of green or white individual petals, or of pure, pale blue. Several small golden berry clusters, made from small granulations of gold are in the middle of each. Four petalled, smaller, blue blooms also add beauty.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1153" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1153" style="width: 500px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-1153" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/1469227001-1.jpg?resize=500%2C558&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="500" height="558" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/1469227001-1.jpg?resize=269%2C300&amp;ssl=1 269w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/1469227001-1.jpg?resize=918%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 918w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/1469227001-1.jpg?resize=768%2C856&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/1469227001-1.jpg?w=1980&amp;ssl=1 1980w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1153" class="wp-caption-text">© The Trustees of the British Museum</figcaption></figure>
<p>Between the bosses there is more enamel ornamentation in darker green and blue. Each has a pale blue rosette in the center from which loops rise, indicating that the ring could have later been worn on a chain, as a pendant. With the elaborate nature of the ring, it probably was not worn on the finger every day.</p>
<p>On the bezel section of the ring, where gemstones on many other types of rings are set, there is a gable, with a hinged roof.  Marriage was considered a transaction between a man and a woman. The gift of a gold ring was measured in its monetary value by being weighed. Adding gemstones was not acceptable as it added to the weight and interfered with determining the value of the gold.  This ring weighs in at 32.2 grams.  It is 4.8 centimeters wide, 2.1 centimeters high, and 3.9 centimeters deep.</p>
<h5>Other Examples</h5>
<p>The British Museum has two other examples of rings with a hinged gable. One has the words “mazel tov” in Hebrew, which means good luck. This indicates this style of ring was created for a Jewish family. It is believed the building represents a couple’s new home together.</p>
<p>This ring in our highlighted example is unique in that it has two windows, which can be opened. The hinged gable can be lifted to reveal a tiny compartment beneath it. To create the look of roof top tiles the artist used more enamel interspersed in colors of blue, white, and green.</p>
<p>No one knows quite when the hinged gable roof style came into fashion.</p>
<h5><strong>Crafted in Eastern Europe</strong></h5>
<p>Some Historians believe rings such as this one had origins in Eastern European regions, such as Transylvania or the Eastern Mediterranean. This is because of the techniques and combination of filigree, with brightly colored and opaque enamels.</p>
<p>Many pieces, using this combined technique in jewelry making, yet are non-Jewish in character, can be found at the National Museum in Budapest. These are Transylvanian in origin and date to the 17<sup>th</sup> and 18<sup>th</sup> centuries. Examples show boldly colored enamels, with twisted filagree and granulations.</p>
<p>Two similar rings have appeared in publication. One is in a private collection<sup>1</sup> and one at the Metropolitan Museum of Art<sup>2</sup>. Both are attributed to Italian Renaissance jewelry, yet there is no documentation to support either.  There is no evidence that jewelry in this style was created in Western Europe. Renaissance Venice has been suggested because of its own resident business colony in Constantinople.</p>
<p>The National Museum of Bucharest houses a large waist-clasp or buckle, that has been identified as 18<sup>th</sup> century Transylvanian. Although it is non-Jewish in nature, it too combines filigree, granulation, and enamel work. Six petalled floral motifs and green enamel work, make it similar in design to the Jewish marriage-ring<sup>3</sup>.</p>
<h5><strong>A Historical Look at Jewish Marriage Rings</strong></h5>
<p>The history of Jewish marriage-rings has not been well documented. There are examples however that date back to the Middle Ages.</p>
<p>The Duke of Bavaria owned a golden ring that was documented and inventoried in 1598. Historians have dated it to the 15<sup>th</sup> century.</p>
<p>The ring houses a miniature Gothic style building representing the Holy Temple set high on the bezel and measuring 4.3 centimeters. It contains the Hebrew inscription “mazal tov”.</p>
<p>Jewish marriage-rings are a tradition that has carried on through the Middle Ages. They represent the union of the couple in celebrational style that has enabled artists to create very elaborate miniature works of golden art.</p>
<ol>
<li>Illustrated in Hackenbroch 1979, p. 52, fig. 112.</li>
<li>G. C. Williamson, ‘Catalogue of the Collection of Jewels and Precious Works of Art, The Property of J. Pierpont Morgan’, London, 1910, no. 20, and Yvonne Hackenbroch, ‘Renaissance Jewellery’, Sotheby Parke Bernet Publications, London, New York and Munich, 1979, p. 50, fig. 105)</li>
<li>Sandor Mihalik, ‘Old Hungarian Enamels’, Budapest, 1961, pp. 28-32, pls 42, 43 and 45.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Bibliographic references</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.britishmuseum.org/collection/term/BIB1846">Read 1902 / The Waddesdon Bequest. Catalogue of the Works of Art Bequeathed to the British Museum by Baron Ferdinand Rothschild, M.P., 1898</a> (195)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.britishmuseum.org/collection/term/BIB1437">Dalton 1912 / Franks Bequest Catalogue of the Finger Rings, Early Christian, Byzantine, Teutonic, Mediaeval and Later, Bequeathed by Sir Augustus Wollaston Franks, KCB, in which are included the other rings of the same period in the Museum.</a> (1337)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.britishmuseum.org/collection/term/BIB10225">Dalton 1927 / The Waddesdon Bequest : jewels, plate, and other works of art bequeathed by Baron Ferdinand Rothschild.</a> (195)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.britishmuseum.org/collection/term/BIB1944">Tait 1986 / Catalogue of the Waddesdon Bequest in the British Museum; I The Jewels</a> (51)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.britishmuseum.org/collection/term/AUTH231124">Shirley and Thornton 2017 / A Rothschild Renaissance: A New Look at the Waddesdon Bequest in the British Museum</a> (p.53, fig.67)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1146</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Elite Learning in Byzantium</title>
		<link>https://medievalarthistory.org/the-elite-learning-in-byzantine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Medieval Art History]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 14:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Early European and Colonial Americas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Medieval Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Medieval Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://medievalarthistory.org/?p=1031</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Elite Learning in Byzantium The Early Byzantium exudes a Christian-Hellenistic duality. The mythologically decorated silverware of Byzantium sets a &#8230; <span class="more-button"><a href="https://medievalarthistory.org/the-elite-learning-in-byzantine/" class="more-link">Continue Reading<span class="screen-reader-text">The Elite Learning in Byzantium</span></a></span>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>The Elite Learning in Byzantium</h2>
<blockquote><p>The Early Byzantium exudes a Christian-Hellenistic duality. The mythologically decorated silverware of Byzantium sets a trap for us, the one of the pagan subject – only to force us to later acknowledge that the nymphs and satyrs were replaced in by revelers of a prosperous proto-Christian world in which the Byzantine elites banqueted and triumphed like the Greek and Roman gods themselves.</p></blockquote>
<p>The ruling classes of Byzantium were defined by paideia-learning. The young Byzantines learned science in the pagan Hellenistic way based on nature, on things, on the universe, which allowed them to &#8220;situate themselves&#8221; in the world. They also learned using Graeco-Roman and Christian texts. These &#8220;classical&#8221; texts not only that offered support for their thought, but also carried a long tradition, and eventually integrated the elite children in a culture shared both with their ancestors and with their contemporaries.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1033" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1033" style="width: 990px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-1033 size-large" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Bowl-with-Dionysiac-Procession-B.jpg?resize=990%2C524&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="990" height="524" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Bowl-with-Dionysiac-Procession-B.jpg?resize=1024%2C542&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Bowl-with-Dionysiac-Procession-B.jpg?resize=300%2C159&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Bowl-with-Dionysiac-Procession-B.jpg?resize=768%2C407&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Bowl-with-Dionysiac-Procession-B.jpg?resize=1536%2C814&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Bowl-with-Dionysiac-Procession-B.jpg?w=1650&amp;ssl=1 1650w" sizes="(max-width: 990px) 100vw, 990px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1033" class="wp-caption-text">Dionysos Entering the Early Byzantium Dining Scene, Bowl with Dionysiac Procession (Old Dionysos and Ariadne, Male Dancer) © The Dumbarton Oaks</figcaption></figure>
<p>While Christianity prevailed in the Byzantine empire, the Hellenistic influence was also strong to the point of transcending regimes, ideologies and political upheavals. Excerpted and annotated the Graeco-Roman texts were used to erect the solid foundation of that constituted the unique Byzantine culture. The thread of this classical tradition is perceptible in the <strong>Byzantine collection of silverware sets of the Dumbarton Oaks Museum</strong>.</p>
<p>Brief reminders of the classical texts and their historical development allowed art historians to decode the meaning and role of the mythologically inspired silverware, such as the<strong> <em>Bowl with a Dionysiac Procession.</em></strong> The mythological aesthetics of <strong>early Byzantine silver-works</strong> are rarely ritualistic, reflecting instead the Byzantine elites’ sophistication and their cultural attachment to the myths and texts defining the Graeco-Roman social values system.<sup>1</sup>This 5th century AC silver bowl adopted neutral revelry motifs, voluntarily reducing the distance between a recently Christianized society and classical Greek culture.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><em>Tertullian&#8217;s Apology for the Christians </em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>&#8220;&#8230; now I see the enormous entertainments, with new names from their extravagance ; &#8230;; and I see mines of silver melted into dishes, &#8230; I see also theatres in abundance, and all indulgingly covered over.&#8221;</em></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Going back in the history of teaching in the West, we encounter Greek children learning the Homeric poems by heart and then preparing themselves, by rhetorical training, for the eloquence of the tribune. In various forms, the learning of the ancient Greece stayed with us, while being extended to new conceptions of the world, whether linked to Christianity, such as scholasticism, or characteristics of the modern world, such as scientific thought.</p>
<p>In modern times, the stakes of teaching the &#8220;Classics&#8221; have continued to shift, but throughout the history of pedagogy in the early Byzantium, the classical texts had an overwhelming position. Mirroring the teachings they received, the elites of the Byzantine empire surrounded themselves with household items underlining the conflicts between their proto-Christian life and their mostly pagan education.</p>
<p>The bishops&#8217; homilies continuously spoke against the duality magic for more than seven centuries until the Council in Trullo (691-692AC), gaining ground slowly but steadily.<sup>2</sup> At a first glance <strong>the Dyonisian engravings</strong> on the Dumbarton Oaks silver bowl seem to support the the thesis of a ritual use. Yet, numerous elements support the bowl’s ornamental value.</p>
<p>The <strong>imagery honored the Dionysian festivals</strong>, traditionally associated with the immutable spring revival and a trade facilitating change in the Mediterranean winds. Presumably, the spring’s increased food stability encouraged the Byzantines to overlook the patristic fathers’ vehement condemnation of banquets.<sup>3</sup>, and maintain the Greek festivals’ social traditions of food distribution accompanied by music, dance and theatrical performances.<sup>4,5</sup></p>
<p>Technically, the <strong>repoussé and chasing</strong> require thin walls, creating fragile objects. Indeed, the bowl’s lower register is damaged, preserving only few fragments of panthers and leaves. Lacking a double wall, the bowl presumably held grapes, and enhanced the owner’s financial security.<sup>6</sup></p>
<p>Given the <strong>gold coinage</strong> stability during the early Byzantine Empire, the elites also acquired <strong>silver objects</strong> to display, or to melt if needed.<sup>7,8</sup></p>
<p>The well-crafted main <strong>register showcases Dionysos’ biography</strong> from his youth to his marriage, and his old age spent in the arms of Ariadne, his wife. The theme of Dionysos’ spiritual evolution betrays a Christian influence.<sup>9</sup> The Dionysian procession is altered; gone are the Hellenistic satyrs, masks, flutes, and tambourines.<sup>10</sup></p>
<p>The <strong>female figures</strong> are depicted dancing, reclining partially nude, and serving wine. Horse-pulled chariots and panthers bring in the <strong>partygoers.</strong> Undeniably, the decoration visually integrates the mythological Dionysian theme with the Byzantine festivities, replacing the <strong>nymphs, and ecstatic maenads</strong> with banquet or triumph revelers.</p>
<p>The association of <strong>dance</strong> with intimacy reinforces the Christian prejudice against non-gendered spaces and stigmatizes artists as sexually available.<sup>13</sup> The tension between Hellenistic and self-controlled Christian ideals also emerges in the stumbling Hercules and the dancing man holding grapes.<sup>14</sup> Resembling a drunk Silenus, the young dancer advances towards Dionysus. His torso twisted in a feminine Salome-like pose suggests an erotic play.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1034" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1034" style="width: 514px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-1034 " src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Bowl-with-Dionysiac-Procession-A.jpg?resize=514%2C691&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="514" height="691" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Bowl-with-Dionysiac-Procession-A.jpg?resize=762%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 762w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Bowl-with-Dionysiac-Procession-A.jpg?resize=223%2C300&amp;ssl=1 223w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Bowl-with-Dionysiac-Procession-A.jpg?resize=768%2C1032&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Bowl-with-Dionysiac-Procession-A.jpg?w=1042&amp;ssl=1 1042w" sizes="(max-width: 514px) 100vw, 514px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1034" class="wp-caption-text">Bowl with Dionysiac Procession<br />(Male Dancer holding grapes)<br />© The Dumbarton Oaks</figcaption></figure>
<p>Metaphorically, the bowl exposes the banquets’ ability to efface the emerging Christian conventions and blur the gender boundaries. The profane reality of the Byzantine life, whose abundant manifestations could not easily disappear thwarted for centuries the imperial Christianization plans ultimately spawning a Christian society deeply rooted in the classical culture.</p>
<ol>
<li>.Ihor Ševčenko, “ A Shadow Outline of Virtue: The Classical Heritage of Greek Christian Literature (Second to Seventh Century),” in <em style="font-size: 1.0625rem;">Age of Spirituality: A </em>Christian Literature (Second to Seventh Century),” in <em style="font-size: 1.0625rem;">Age of Spirituality: A </em><em style="font-size: 1.0625rem;">Symposium, </em><span style="font-size: 1.0625rem;">ed. Kurt Weitzmann, (New York: Princeton University Press and The </span>Metropolitan Museum, 1980), 55-56,</li>
</ol>
<p><a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.metmuseum.org%2Fart%2Fmetpublications%2Fage_of_spirituality_a_symposium&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNH0avhN7DIcfIOYZebhXOarkCzGcA">https://www.metmuseum.org/art/metpublications/age_of_spirituality_a_symposiu</a></p>
<ol start="2">
<li>.Lionel Casson, &#8220;Speed under Sail of Ancient Ships,” <em>Transactions and</em> <em>Proceedings of the American Philological Association 82 </em>(1951): 147, <a href="https://sites.google.com/ucsc.edu/dionysos-in-byzantium/home?read_current=1#BAD_URL">https://doi:10.2307/283426 </a>.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="3">
<li>John Chrysostom, “Homily 48 on Mathew,” in <em>Nicene and Post-Nicene Fathers,</em> <em>First Series</em>, Vol. 10, ed. Philip Schaff, trans. George Prevost, rev. M.B. Riddle. (Buffalo, NY: Christian Literature Publishing Co., 1888), rev. and ed. Kevin Knight, New Advent. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.newadvent.org%2Ffathers%2F200148.htm&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEfbUmEy0L-B1cmTc_s-7dhz2Ts2g">http://www.newadvent.org/fathers/200148.htm </a>.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="4">
<li>N. Belknap, ”The Social Value of Dionysiac Ritual,” <em>Revue De L&#8217;histoire Des</em> <em>Religions </em>106 (1932): 575-580.</li>
<li>Eric Csapo, “The Dionysian Parade and the Poetics of Plenitude,” <em>The</em> <em>Department of Greek and Latin at University College London Housman Lectures: </em>1-5, February 20, 2013, <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ucl.ac.uk%2Fclassics%2Fsites%2Fclassics%2Ffiles%2Fhousman.csapo_.2013.pdf&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNE86yIbgaDQJgvslPV4zEl1lGsUvw">https://www.ucl.ac.uk/classics/sites/classics/files/housman.csapo_.2013.pdf </a>.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="6">
<li>Katerina Panagopoulou, &#8220;Between Necessity and Extravagance: Silver as a Commodity in the Hellenistic Period,” <em>The Annual of the British School at Athens</em> 102 (2007): 315-318.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="7">
<li>Peter Guest, &#8220;The Production, Supply and Use of Late Roman and Early Byzantine Copper Coinage in the Eastern Empire,” <em>The Numismatic Chronicle</em> <em>(1966-) </em>172 (2012): 107.</li>
<li>“The History of Byzantine coinage,“ Dumbarton Oaks, accessed July 22, 2021, <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.doaks.org%2Fvisit%2Fmuseum%2Fexhibitions%2Fpast%2Fcoinage-of-the-byzantine-empire%2Fonline%2FIntroduction%2FFrame_Introduction.html&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEB5gctl8ELVRUOc5iQXfEuWPOGaA">https://www.doaks.org/visit/museum/exhibitions/past/coinage-of-the-byzantine-</a><a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.doaks.org%2Fvisit%2Fmuseum%2Fexhibitions%2Fpast%2Fcoinage-of-the-byzantine-empire%2Fonline%2FIntroduction%2FFrame_Introduction.html&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEB5gctl8ELVRUOc5iQXfEuWPOGaA">empire/online/Introduction/Frame_Introduction.html . </a></li>
</ol>
<ol start="9">
<li>David Parrish, &#8220;A Mythological Theme in the Decoration of Late Roman Dining Rooms: Dionysos and His Circle,” <em>Revue Archéologique</em>, no. 2 (1995): 325.</li>
<li>“The Mildenhall Bacchic platter,” British Museum, accessed July 22, 2021, <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.britishmuseum.org%2Fcollection%2Fobject%2FH_1946-1007-1&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGyepnu4qTFKoH0doBaUWrMdiCrNw">https://www.britishmuseum.org/collection/object/H_1946-1007-1 </a>.</li>
<li>David Parrish, &#8220;A Mythological Theme in the Decoration of Late Roman Dining Rooms: Dionysos and His Circle,” Revue Archéologique, no.2 (1995): 310-311, 316-322, 332.</li>
<li>Orgu Dalgic, &#8220;The Triumph of Dionysos in Constantinople: A Late Fifth-Century Mosaic in Context,” <em style="font-size: 1.0625rem;">Dumbarton Oaks Papers</em><span style="font-size: 1.0625rem;"> 69 (2015): 17-18.</span></li>
<li>Ruth Webb, “Salome’s Sisters. The Rhetoric and Realities of Dance in Late Antiquity and Byzantium,” in <em>Women, men, and eunuchs : gender in Byzantium,</em> Liz James, (London ; New York : Routledge, 1997) 122-123, 127, 136-137.</li>
<li>“Bowl with Dionysiac Procession,” Dumbarton Oaks, accessed July 20, 2021, <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fmuseum.doaks.org%2Fobjects-1%2Finfo%2F36036&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFPXdp4ZFmP49vRVg625mlG8SYRJQ">http://museum.doaks.org/objects-1/info/36036 </a>.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Acknowlegments</strong></p>
<p>The author thanks Dr. McGuire and Dr. Lodwick of University of California at Santa Cruz for feedback she received on her research.</p>
<p><strong>References: </strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Belknap, G. N. &#8220;The Social Value of Dionysiac Ritual.&#8221; <em>Revue De L&#8217;histoire Des</em> <em>Religions </em>106 (1932): 575-91. Accessed July 19, 2021. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.jstor.org%2Fstable%2F23664842&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNHl4ZwM136XiI3Z40PzTACjQVm20w">http://www.jstor.org/stable/23664842 </a>.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="2">
<li>British Museum. “The Mildenhall Bacchic platter.” Accessed July 22, 2021. <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.britishmuseum.org%2Fcollection%2Fobject%2FH_1946-1007-1&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGyepnu4qTFKoH0doBaUWrMdiCrNw">https://www.britishmuseum.org/collection/object/H_1946-1007-1 </a>.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="3">
<li>Casson, Lionel. &#8220;Speed under Sail of Ancient Ships.&#8221; <em>Transactions and</em> <em>Proceedings of the American Philological Association </em>82 (1951): 136-48. <a href="https://sites.google.com/ucsc.edu/dionysos-in-byzantium/home?read_current=1#BAD_URL">https://doi:10.2307/283426 </a>.</li>
<li>Chrysostom, John. “Homily 48 Mathew” In <em>Nicene and Post-Nicene Fathers, First</em> <em>Series</em>, Vol. 10. Edited by Philip Schaff. Translated by George Prevost and revised by M.B. Riddle. Buffalo, NY: Christian Literature Publishing Co., 1888. Revised and edited for New Advent by Kevin Knight, Revised and edited for New Advent by Kevin Knight, <a style="font-size: 1.0625rem;" href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.newadvent.org%2Ffathers%2F200148.htm&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEfbUmEy0L-B1cmTc_s-7dhz2Ts2g">http://www.newadvent.org/fathers/200148.htm </a><span style="font-size: 1.0625rem;">.</span></li>
</ol>
<ol start="5">
<li>Csapo, Eric. “The Dionysian Parade and the Poetics of Plenitude.” <em>The</em> <em>Department of Greek and Latin at University College London Housman Lectures, </em>February 20, 2013. <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ucl.ac.uk%2Fclassics%2Fsites%2Fclassics%2Ffiles%2Fhousman.csapo_.2013.pdf&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNE86yIbgaDQJgvslPV4zEl1lGsUvw">https://www.ucl.ac.uk/classics/sites/classics/files/housman.csapo_.2013.pdf </a>.</li>
<li>Dalgic, Orgu. &#8220;The Triumph of Dionysos in Constantinople: A Late Fifth-Century Mosaic in Context.&#8221; <em style="font-size: 1.0625rem;">Dumbarton Oaks Papers</em><span style="font-size: 1.0625rem;"> 69 (2015): 15-48. </span><a style="font-size: 1.0625rem;" href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.jstor.org%2Fstable%2F26497708&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNF21NcioyxkTTJ2UU13VmyQN1TFpg">https://www.jstor.org/stable/26497708 </a><span style="font-size: 1.0625rem;">.</span></li>
</ol>
<ol start="7">
<li>Dumbarton Oaks. “Bowl with Dionysiac Procession.” Accessed July 20, 2021. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fmuseum.doaks.org%2Fobjects-1%2Finfo%2F36036&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFPXdp4ZFmP49vRVg625mlG8SYRJQ">http://museum.doaks.org/objects-1/info/36036 </a>.</li>
<li>Dumbarton Oaks. “The History of Byzantine coinage.“ Accessed July 22, 2021. <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.doaks.org%2Fvisit%2Fmuseum%2Fexhibitions%2Fpast%2Fcoinage-of-the-byzantine-empire%2Fonline%2FIntroduction%2FFrame_Introduction.html&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEB5gctl8ELVRUOc5iQXfEuWPOGaA">https://www.doaks.org/visit/museum/exhibitions/past/coinage-of-the-byzantine-</a><a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.doaks.org%2Fvisit%2Fmuseum%2Fexhibitions%2Fpast%2Fcoinage-of-the-byzantine-empire%2Fonline%2FIntroduction%2FFrame_Introduction.html&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEB5gctl8ELVRUOc5iQXfEuWPOGaA">empire/online/Introduction/Frame_Introduction.html . </a></li>
</ol>
<ol start="9">
<li>Guest, Peter. &#8220;The Production, Supply and Use of Late Roman and Early Byzantine Copper Coinage in the Eastern Empire.&#8221; <em>The Numismatic Chronicle</em> <em>(1966-) </em>172 (2012): 105-131. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.jstor.org%2Fstable%2F42678933&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNE8Gt6xX90I5J2BRqOQycvY62EpyA">http://www.jstor.org/stable/42678933 </a>. <em style="font-size: 1.0625rem;"> </em></li>
</ol>
<ol start="10">
<li>Panagopoulou, Katerina. &#8220;Between Necessity and Extravagance: Silver as a Commodity in the Hellenistic Period.&#8221; <em>The Annual of the British School at Athens</em> 102 (2007): 315-343. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.jstor.org%2Fstable%2F30245253&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNEaQm_6aNd2qW-U_r9tOPnY3Bx7tQ">http://www.jstor.org/stable/30245253 </a>.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="11">
<li>Parrish, David. &#8220;A Mythological Theme in the Decoration of Late Roman Dining Rooms: Dionysos and His Circle.&#8221; <em>Revue Archéologique</em>, no. 2 (1995): 307-32. <a href="http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.jstor.org%2Fstable%2F41737826&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNFU1M3tl-Ly5xTwTuwsBB8neUgcUQ">http://www.jstor.org/stable/41737826 </a>.</li>
<li>Ševčenko, Ihor. “ A Shadow Outline of Virtue: The Classical Heritage of Greek Christian Literature (Second to Seventh Century).” In <em style="font-size: 1.0625rem;">Age of Spirituality: A </em><em style="font-size: 1.0625rem;">Symposium, </em><span style="font-size: 1.0625rem;">edited by Kurt Weitzmann, 53-74. New York: Princeton University Press and The Metropolitan Museum, 1980 </span><a style="font-size: 1.0625rem;" href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.metmuseum.org%2Fart%2Fmetpublications%2Fage_of_spirituality_a_symposium&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNH0avhN7DIcfIOYZebhXOarkCzGcA">https://www.metmuseum.org/art/metpublications/age_of_spirituality_a_symposiu</a> <a style="font-size: 1.0625rem;" href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.metmuseum.org%2Fart%2Fmetpublications%2Fage_of_spirituality_a_symposium&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNH0avhN7DIcfIOYZebhXOarkCzGcA">m .</a></li>
</ol>
<ol start="13">
<li>“Chapter VI: That The Romans Are Mighty Praisers of the Antiquity of Their Religion, and Yet Admit of Novelties into It Everyday.” In <em style="font-size: 1.0625rem;">The Apology of</em> <em style="font-size: 1.0625rem;">Tertullian</em><span style="font-size: 1.0625rem;">,</span><em style="font-size: 1.0625rem;"> 20-24</em><span style="font-size: 1.0625rem;">. Vol. 31 of</span><em style="font-size: 1.0625rem;"> The Ancient &amp; Modern Library of Theological Literature</em><span style="font-size: 1.0625rem;">. 6th edition. Translated by William M Reeve. London and Sydney: Newberry House, 1889. </span><a style="font-size: 1.0625rem;" href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.tertullian.org%2Farticles%2Freeve_apology.htm&amp;sa=D&amp;sntz=1&amp;usg=AFQjCNGTzR6FjkA5VMnFqJT_1Eyg3geUbQ">https://www.tertullian.org/articles/reeve_apology.htm </a><span style="font-size: 1.0625rem;">. </span></li>
</ol>
<ol start="14">
<li>Webb, Ruth. “Salome’s Sisters. The Rhetoric and Realities of Dance in Late Antiquity and Byzantium.” In <em>Women, men, and eunuchs : gender in Byzantium,</em> edited by Liz James, 119-148. London, New York : Routledge, 1997.</li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>References:</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1031</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unveiling the World of Byzantine Brides</title>
		<link>https://medievalarthistory.org/unveiling-the-world-of-byzantine-brides/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Medieval Art History]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 20:04:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Early European and Colonial Americas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Medieval Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Medieval Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://medievalarthistory.org/?p=750</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Unveiling the World of the Byzantine Brides Their Hopes, Their Fears and The Societal Expectations World of signs, of the &#8230; <span class="more-button"><a href="https://medievalarthistory.org/unveiling-the-world-of-byzantine-brides/" class="more-link">Continue Reading<span class="screen-reader-text">Unveiling the World of Byzantine Brides</span></a></span>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Unveiling the World of the Byzantine Brides</h2>
<h4><span data-ri="0">Their Hopes, Their Fears and The Societal Expectations</span></h4>
<figure id="attachment_752" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-752" style="width: 990px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-752 size-large" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Byzantine-finger-ring-5th-century-ACAF.232-©-The-Trustees-of-the-British-Museum.png?resize=990%2C540&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="990" height="540" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Byzantine-finger-ring-5th-century-ACAF.232-©-The-Trustees-of-the-British-Museum.png?resize=1024%2C559&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Byzantine-finger-ring-5th-century-ACAF.232-©-The-Trustees-of-the-British-Museum.png?resize=300%2C164&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Byzantine-finger-ring-5th-century-ACAF.232-©-The-Trustees-of-the-British-Museum.png?resize=768%2C419&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Byzantine-finger-ring-5th-century-ACAF.232-©-The-Trustees-of-the-British-Museum.png?resize=1536%2C838&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Byzantine-finger-ring-5th-century-ACAF.232-©-The-Trustees-of-the-British-Museum.png?resize=2048%2C1117&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Byzantine-finger-ring-5th-century-ACAF.232-©-The-Trustees-of-the-British-Museum.png?w=1980&amp;ssl=1 1980w" sizes="(max-width: 990px) 100vw, 990px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-752" class="wp-caption-text">Byzantine finger-ring 5th century AC(AF.232) © The Trustees of the British Museum</figcaption></figure>
<blockquote><p><em>World of signs, of the transcendental, and of the imaginary, <strong>Byzantium</strong> is whole only in its Christian-Hellenistic duality. </em></p></blockquote>
<h5>The Layers of Meaning of a Byzantine  Ring</h5>
<p>A marriage in Byzantium evokes the embroidered gowns and <span data-ri="1">pearl-studded </span><span data-ri="2">crowns promoted by the imperial mosaics adorning the Byzantine Churches from Ravenna to Constantinople. The Byzantine marriage objects that have come down to us, mostly from buried treasures or burials, are not very numerous. However, they exposed the much less noticeable <strong>finger-ring</strong> as the quintessential element of a Byzantine marriage</span><span data-ri="3">.</span><sup><span data-ri="4">1</span></sup></p>
<p><span data-ri="6">Usually worn on the third finger, the marriage rings were not reserved for women, being also popular with men.</span><sup><span data-ri="7">1</span></sup><span data-ri="8"> Along with other bridal luxury gifts &#8211; ivory caskets, pyxides, and gold marriage  belts- the AF.232 British Museum <strong>gold finger-ring</strong> was reserved for the upper classes of the early Byzantine Empire.</span><sup><span data-ri="9">2,3</span></sup></p>
<p><span data-ri="10">The more modest clientele used less noble metals, even if the misspelled “OM(o)NYA-concord” bezel inscription, and the rather crude engravings  on the ring’s bezel reflect more the owner’s wealth than her rank. Although the ring’s figural iconography articulates an overtly Christian visual propaganda, apparently neutral design elements unveil how the <strong>pagan rituals and Christianity coalesced into a hidden message</strong> of universal intercession and protection for the ring’s owner. </span></p>
<figure id="attachment_752" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-752" style="width: 990px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-961 size-large" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-09-04-at-10.30.17-PM.png?resize=990%2C800&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="990" height="800" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-752" class="wp-caption-text">Octagonal Hoop Inscription <span data-ri="1">(John 14:27), Byzantine finger-ring 5th century AC(AF.232) © The Trustees of the British Museum</span></figcaption></figure>
<h4><strong><em>Mark 10:9  &#8220;What G-d had joined together &#8230; &#8220;</em></strong></h4>
<p>Following the 337AC conversion of the emperor Constantine, Christian art triumphed. The early Christian apologists considered the offering of a gold ring an ancestral marriage custom, free of pagan stigma.<sup><span data-ri="2">4</span></sup> <span data-ri="4"> Mirroring signet rings, the women marriage rings could b</span><span data-ri="5">e</span><span data-ri="6"> used to authenticate documents and secure household items, underlining a Christian wife’s role in administering the family wealth.</span><sup><span data-ri="7">5,6</span></sup><span data-ri="8">  </span></p>
<p><span data-ri="8">We can easily distinguish in this 6th-7th centuries AC ring a young art, whose lively imagination is enchanted by <strong>Christian symbols</strong> and welded with the reasoned expression of <strong>classical art.</strong> The ring metalworking process seems borrowed directly from late Roman goldsmiths. However, the Byzantine aesthetic heightened the taste for polychromy, expressed here by the use of black niello. </span></p>
<p><span data-ri="8">The symmetrical composition of the bezel reflects the relative equality of rights of the couple.</span><sup><span data-ri="9">7</span></sup> <span data-ri="11">T</span><span data-ri="12">he bride and groom are dressed formally in a modest “tunica recta” and, respectively, a “chlamys” hold in place with a l</span><span data-ri="13">arge</span><span data-ri="14"> fibula. Their heads are joyfully crowned with Roman nuptial wreaths, or coin-inspired spiked imperial headgears.</span><sup><span data-ri="15">8</span></sup><span data-ri="16"> The bride was not veiled. </span></p>
<p><span data-ri="16">The Christian identity of the ring owner, however, filtered her understanding of the Roman concept of marital harmony. Exuding an imperial marriage solidus vibe, <strong>the ring’s central figure is Christ</strong>. He is engraved at a slightly larger scale to emphasize the importance of his role. Christ acts as “deus pronubus” replacing the Roman goddesses Juno and Concordia. Christ only touches the couple shoulders to unite them in marriage. They do not join their right hands together in the Roman marital “dextrarum iunctio”. </span></p>
<p><span data-ri="16">Christ’s crossed halo emphasizes his sacrifice, while the abridged <strong>John 14:27</strong> verse on the hoop <strong>“Peace I leave with you; my peace I give you“</strong> highlights the Christian belief that only God’s grace leads to universal harmony, not human acts.</span><sup><span data-ri="17">9</span></sup></p>
<h5><strong>The Mysterious Star</strong></h5>
<p><span data-ri="18"> The adoption of the theory-cult of Virgin Mary might have played a role in the choice of a <strong>star engraving below the bride’s feet</strong>. Remarkably, this mysterious star appears on only one other British Museum Byzantine ring</span><span data-ri="19">. This second ring features back to back Christ and the Virgin blessing the newlyweds. The </span><span data-ri="20">star is engraved above the Virgin.</span><sup><span data-ri="21">10</span></sup></p>
<p><span data-ri="22">Concurrently, the mosaics of Sant’Apollinare Nuovo Basilica also depicted a star gleaming on the enthroned Virgin’s veil.</span><sup><span data-ri="23">1</span><span data-ri="24">1</span></sup><span data-ri="25"> The later Orthodox Church iconography connected the three stars adorning the veil of Mary Theotokos -“Mother of God” to her alleged triple “virgin” status: before, during, and after her pregnancy with Christ.</span><sup><span data-ri="26">1</span><span data-ri="27">2</span></sup><span data-ri="28"> Thus, it seems possible that <strong>the star symbolized the virgin status of the bride.</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 1.0625rem;"> </span></p>
<figure id="attachment_753" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-753" style="width: 990px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-753" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-09-04-at-10.36.57-PM.png?resize=990%2C560&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="990" height="560" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-753" class="wp-caption-text">A Similar Byzantine finger-ring (AF.231) © The Trustees of the British Museum</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_753" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-753" style="width: 900px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-968" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-07-05-at-8.38.15-PM.png?resize=900%2C500&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="900" height="500" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-753" class="wp-caption-text">Virgin Enthroned with Starred Veil, Sant’Apollinare Nuovo Basilica, Ravenna</figcaption></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5><strong><em>1 Thessalonians 5:8  &#8220;Let us, who are of the day, be sober, putting on the breastplate of faith and love; and for an helmet, the hope of salvation.&#8221;</em></strong></h5>
<p>The association between the Byzantine bride imagery and the Virgin Mary has, however, its limitations, as Byzantine women <strong>fertility was often celebrated</strong> with mixed visual messages. Fear, death, hope, and desire all loomed above marital happiness and childbirth, dividing the ring meanings between the <strong>Christian expectations</strong> and the <strong>Hellenistic customs</strong> of warding off evil. The medico-magical rituals of the Kyranides book, the erotic Dionysian rites, and the <span data-ri="2">poems of Dioscorus of Aphrodito commingled with Christianity</span><span data-ri="3">.</span><span data-ri="4"><sup>13</sup></span></p>
<p><span data-ri="6"> Recognizable Annunciation images, and Christ officiating under a canopy, presumably at the Jewish marriage in Cana were engraved together with “protective” biblical inscriptions in the Byzantine &#8220;Christian amulets&#8221;.</span><span data-ri="9"><sup>14</sup></span></p>
<p><span data-ri="10">To address such derives, the bishops continuously enacted <strong>punishments against magic</strong> for more than three centuries, from the early legislative acts of the Emperor Constantius II (337-361AC) to the ones of the Council in Trullo (691-692AC).</span><span data-ri="13"><sup>15</sup></span><span data-ri="15"> The alleged magical childbirth amulets of the ring were its octagonal bezel and hoop, as well as the “OM(o)NYA” inscription.</span><span data-ri="16"><sup>16,17,18 </sup></span></p>
<p><span data-ri="18"><strong>Octagons</strong> were popular among the early Christians, possibly referencing Christ’s resurrection and their own rebirth hopes. The engraved “protective” verse also seems to reinforce the magical shield of the ring since the unabridged text John 14:27 urges Christians to have faith and not be afraid.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<figure id="attachment_754" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-754" style="width: 990px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-967 size-large" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-07-22-at-1.32.11-AM.png?resize=990%2C900&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="990" height="900" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-754" class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Amulet&#8221; with Annunciation and Christ (H1938,1010.1) © The Trustees of the British Museum</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_754" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-754" style="width: 990px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-969 size-large" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/Screen-Shot-2021-09-04-at-10.46.53-PM.png?resize=990%2C900&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="990" height="900" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-754" class="wp-caption-text">Prototype of the Byzantine Icon &#8220;Theotokos of Passion&#8221; with a triple starred veil, © The Antioch Patriachate</figcaption></figure>
<p>Taken together, the ring’s <strong>Hellenistic and Christian elements</strong> convey a nuanced and syncretic message of perpetual protection for the couple. At a larger scale, the persistence of magic in the progressively Christianized Byzantine society illustrates the interwoven coexistence of two radically different belief systems.</p>
<ol>
<li style="list-style-type: none;">
<ol>
<li>Gary Vikan<span data-ri="1">,</span><span data-ri="2"> &#8220;Art and Marriage in Early Byzantium</span><span data-ri="3">,</span><span data-ri="4">&#8221; </span><em><span data-ri="5">Dumbarton Oaks Papers</span></em><span data-ri="6"> 44 (1990): 146, 147, 151</span><span data-ri="7">,</span> <u><span data-ri="9">https://doi.org/10.2307/1291624</span></u><span data-ri="10"> .</span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> Ormonde Maddock Dalton, <em>Catalogue Of Early Christian Antiquities And Objects From The Christian East: In The Department Of British And Mediaeval Antiquities And Ethnography Of The British Museum</em> (London: BMP, 1901), 22 (Ring 130), <u>https://ia600306.us.archive.org/15/items/catalogueofearly00brit/catalogueofearly00brit.pdf</u></span><span data-ri="5"> . </span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> ”Finger-ring 232,” British Museum, accessed July 22, 2021, <u>https://www.britishmuseum.org/collection/object/H_1938-1010-1</u></span><span data-ri="11"> . </span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> Tertullian, “Chapter VI: That The Romans Are Mighty Praisers of the Antiquity of Their Religion, and Yet Admit of Novelties into It Everyday,” in <em>The Apology of Tertullian</em>, vol.31 of <em>The Ancient &amp; Modern Library of Theological Literature</em>, William M Reeve, 6th ed. (London and Sydney: Newberry House, 1889), 21, </span><span data-ri="9"><u>https://www.tertullian.org/articles/reeve_apology.htm</u></span><span data-ri="10"> . </span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> Gary Vikan, &#8220;Art and Marriage in Early Byzantium,&#8221; <em>Dumbarton Oaks Papers</em> 44 (1990): 146, 147, 151, <u>https://doi.org/10.2307/1291624</u></span><span data-ri="10"> . </span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> John Chrysostom, “The Kind of Women Who Ought to be Taken as Wives,” in <em>Women in Early Christianity: Translations from Greek Texts, </em> Patricia Cox Miller (Washington: Catholic University of America Press, 2005), 271, ProQuest Ebook Central. </span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> Thomas Yan, “The Division of Sexes in Roman Law,” in <em>From Ancient Goddesses to Christian Saints</em>, ed. Pauline Shmitt Pantel, Vol.1 of <em>A History of Women in the West, </em></span><span data-ri="5">series eds. Georges Duby and Michelle Perrot, trans. Arthur Goldhammer</span> <span data-ri="7">(Cambridge: The Belknap Press of Harvard Univ. Press, 2002), 91. </span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> Gary Vikan, &#8220;Art and Marriage in Early Byzantium,&#8221; <em>Dumbarton Oaks Papers</em> 44 (1990): 147, 157, </span><span data-ri="8"><u>https://doi.org/10.2307/1291624</u></span><span data-ri="9"> . </span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> Ernst H. Kantorowicz, “On the Golden Marriage Belt and the Marriage Rings of the Dumbarton Oaks Collection,” <em>Dumbarton Oaks Papers</em> 14 (1960): 9,11, <u>https://doi.org/10.2307/1291142</u></span><span data-ri="5"> . </span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> Ormonde Maddock Dalton, <em>Catalogue Of Early Christian Antiquities And Objects From The Christian East: In The Department Of British And Mediaeval Antiquities And Ethnography Of The British Museum</em> (London: BMP, 1901), 21 (Ring 129), </span><span data-ri="4"><u>https://ia600306.us.archive.org/15/items/catalogueofearly00brit/catalogueofearly00brit.pdf</u></span><span data-ri="5"> . </span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> Beth Harris and Steven Zucker, “Sant’Apollinare Nuovo, Ravenna,” SmartHistory, filmed April 2021, video, 5:13, <u>https://smarthistory.org/santapollinare-nuovo/</u></span><span data-ri="5"> . </span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> ”Icons Explanation. The “Theotokos of Passion” Icon,”  Greek Orthodox Patriarchate of Antioch and All the East, accessed July, 22, 2021,</span><span data-ri="4"> <u>https://www.antiochpatriarchate.org/en/category/24/</u></span><span data-ri="6"> . </span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> Alicia Walker, &#8220;Myth and Magic in Early Byzantine Marriage Jewelry,&#8221; in <em>The Material Culture of Sex, Procreation, and Marriage in Premodern Europe</em>, eds. Anne McClanan and Karen Encarnación (New York: Palgrave Macmillan, 2002), 62, 64, 65-66, 67, <u>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-137-08503-0_4</u></span><span data-ri="7"> . </span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> ”Amulet,” British Museum, </span><span data-ri="1"><u>https://www.britishmuseum.org/collection/object/H_1938-1010-1 </u></span></li>
<li>Alicia Walker, &#8220;Myth and Magic in Early Byzantine Marriage Jewelry,&#8221; in <em>The Material Culture of Sex, Procreation, and Marriage in Premodern Europe</em>, eds. Anne McClanan and Karen Encarnación (New York: Palgrave Macmillan, 2002), 65-66, <u>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-137-08503-0_4</u><span style="font-size: 1.0625rem;" data-ri="7"> . </span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> Gary Vikan, &#8220;Art and Marriage in Early Byzantium,&#8221; <em>Dumbarton Oaks Papers</em> 44 (1990): 155-157, </span><span data-ri="3"><u>https://doi.org/10.2307/1291624</u></span><span data-ri="4"> . </span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> Andrew L. Goldman, “The Octagonal Gemstones from Gordion: Observations and Interpretations,” <em>Anatolian Studies</em> 64 (2014): 176, 182, </span><span data-ri="3"><u>https://doi.org/10.1017/s0066154614000088</u></span><span data-ri="4"> . </span></li>
<li>18. Lois Drewer, “Recent Approaches to Early Christian and Byzantine Iconography,” <em style="font-size: 1.0625rem;"><span data-ri="1">Studies in Iconography</span></em><span style="font-size: 1.0625rem;" data-ri="2"> 17 (1996), 9-10, </span><span style="font-size: 1.0625rem;" data-ri="3"><u>http://www.jstor.org/stable/23923639</u></span></li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Acknowledgements:</strong></p>
<p><span data-ri="0">Anne-Sarah thanks Dr. McGuire and Dr. Lodwick of University of California at Santa Cruz for feedback she received on her research done to establish the meaning of the star below the bride&#8217;s feet.  Pointing out the Annunciation and the Magi,  Dr. McGuire suggested a  wish for safe childbirths. It was a very logical connection, yet I thought it to be too vague for the economy of a bezel. The star probably connected the bride to Mary, but how? Looking up in the Byzantine iconography, I learned that starting 700-800AC Mary’s veil was depicted with three stars symbolizing her triple virginity.  Our back-and-forth debate determined me to keep looking for the missing link &#8211; an early depiction of Mary with only one star.  Once, the argument became stronger, the line of thought accurate and logic, the implementation time came. Dr. Lodwick&#8217;s unconditional support and her many patient answers helped me better my writing and formatting. Thank you.</span><span data-ri="1">  </span></p>
<p><strong>References:</strong></p>
<p>Click to edit text</p>
<ol>
<li><span aria-hidden="true">British Museum. ”Amulet.&#8221; Accessed July 22, 2021. </span><span data-ri="1"><u>https://www.britishmuseum.org/collection/object/H_1938-1010-1</u></span><span data-ri="2"> .</span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> British Museum. “Finger-ring AF.232.” Accessed July 22, 2021. <u>https://www.britishmuseum.org/collection/object/H_AF-232</u> .</span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> Chrysostom, John. “The Kind of Women Who Ought to be Taken as Wives,” in <em>Women in Early Christianity: Translations from Greek Texts, </em>edited by Patricia Cox Miller, 270-272. Washington: Catholic University of America Press, 2005. ProQuest Ebook Central.</span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> Dalton, Ormonde Maddock.  <em>Catalogue Of Early Christian Antiquities And Objects From The Christian East: In The Department Of British And Mediaeval Antiquities And Ethnography Of The British Museum</em>. London: BMP, 1901. <u>https://ia600306.us.archive.org/15/items/catalogueofearly00brit/catalogueofearly00brit.pdf</u> .</span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> Drewer, Lois. “Recent Approaches to Early Christian and Byzantine Iconography.” <em>Studies in Iconography</em> 17 (1996): 1-65. <u>http://www.jstor.org/stable/23923639</u> .</span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> Goldman, Andrew L. &#8220;The Octagonal Gemstones from Gordion: Observations and Interpretations.&#8221; <em>Anatolian Studies </em>64 (2014): 163-97. <u>http://www.jstor.org/stable/24878355</u> .</span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> Greek Orthodox Patriarchate of Antioch and All the East. ”Icons Explanation. The “Theotokos of Passion” Icon.” Accessed July 17, 2021. <u>https://www.antiochpatriarchate.org/en/category/24/</u> .</span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> Harris, Beth and Zucker, Steven. “Sant’Apollinare Nuovo, Ravenna.” SmartHistory. Filmed April 2021. Video, 5:13. <u>https://smarthistory.org/santapollinare-nuovo/</u> .</span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> Kantorowicz, Ernst H. &#8220;On the Golden Marriage Belt and the Marriage Rings of the Dumbarton Oaks Collection.&#8221; <em>Dumbarton Oaks Papers</em> 14 (1960): 1-16. <u>https://doi:10.2307/1291142</u> .</span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> “Chapter VI: That The Romans Are Mighty Praisers of the Antiquity of Their Religion, and Yet Admit of Novelties into It Everyday.” In <em>The Apology of Tertullian</em>,<em> 20-24</em>. Vol. 31 of  <em>The Ancient &amp; Modern Library of Theological Literature</em>. 6th edition. </span><span data-ri="12">Translated by William M Reeve. London and Sydney: Newberry House, 1889. </span><span data-ri="13"><u>https://www.tertullian.org/articles/reeve_apology.htm</u></span><span data-ri="14"> .</span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> Vikan, Gary. &#8220;Art and Marriage in Early Byzantium.&#8221; <em>Dumbarton Oaks Papers</em> 44 (1990): 145-63. <u>https://doi:10.2307/1291624</u> .</span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> Walker, Alicia. “Myth and Magic in Early Byzantine Marriage Jewelry.” In <em>The Material Culture of Sex, Procreation, and Marriage in Premodern Europe, e</em>dited by Anne McClanan and Karen Encarnación, 59–78. New York: Palgrave Macmillan, 2002. <u>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-137-08503-0_4</u> . </span></li>
<li><span data-ri="0"> Yan, Thomas. “The Division of Sexes in Roman Law.” In <em>From Ancient Goddesses to Christian Saints</em>, edited by Pauline Shmitt Pantel, 83-138. Vol.1 of <em>A History of Women in the West,</em> series edited by Georges Duby and Michelle Perrot. Translated by Arthur Goldhammer. Cambridge: The Belknap Press of Harvard Univ. Press, 1994. </span></li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">750</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
