<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Global Prehistory &#8211; MEDIEVAL ART HISTORY</title>
	<atom:link href="https://medievalarthistory.org/category/global-prehistory/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://medievalarthistory.org</link>
	<description>with the AP Art History Course</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 12:33:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">194999971</site>	<item>
		<title>Global Prehistory 1.3</title>
		<link>https://medievalarthistory.org/global-prehistory-1-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Medieval Art History]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 21:56:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP ART HISTORY COURSE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Global Prehistory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://medievalarthistory.org/?p=32</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Global Prehistory  30,000- 500 BCE Theme:  “Cave Conjecture” This theme addresses the “site” caves of much Paleolithic Art as well &#8230; <span class="more-button"><a href="https://medievalarthistory.org/global-prehistory-1-3/" class="more-link">Continue Reading<span class="screen-reader-text">Global Prehistory 1.3</span></a></span>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2><strong>Global Prehistory </strong></h2>
<h3>30,000- 500 BCE</h3>
<figure id="attachment_179" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-179" style="width: 804px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-179" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Running-horned-woman.jpg?resize=804%2C953&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="804" height="953" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-179" class="wp-caption-text">Running horned woman<br />© The Granger Collection, New York</figcaption></figure>
<h3><strong>Theme:  “Cave Conjecture”</strong></h3>
<p>This theme addresses the “site” caves of much Paleolithic Art as well as the lack of documentation.  Therefore, much of this chapter is comprised of conjecture.</p>
<h4><strong>Topic 1.3 Theories and Interpretations of Prehistoric Art  </strong></h4>
<p>Ongoing archaeological excavations and the use of <strong>carbon-14 dating</strong> have illuminated interconnections of art across the world.  This remains conjecture, because of the small number of surviving moments and other that are yet to be found.</p>
<p>Comparisons of groups of objects and the application of ethnographic analogy (considering modern traditional cultural practices as models for ancient ones) and reconstruction of religious history (noting shamanism as the earliest, most persistent worldwide spiritual approach) can be applied to help establish general theories of the function and meaning of prehistoric art.</p>
<h5><strong>How Archeological and Art History Work Together</strong></h5>
<p>Modern stratigraphic archeology or the precise recording of each level and location of all objects, was first used circa 1900. The has served as a basis for art history studies.</p>
<p><strong>Archaeology</strong> supports understandings of how people, culture, and therefore art travelled across the globe, well before highly organized societies were formed. Important monuments, such as the caves at Lascaux, and media, particularly ceramics, were first discovered. Then these artifacts were described by archaeologists. Then, became available for interpretation by art historians.</p>
<h5><strong> A Deeper Understanding</strong></h5>
<p>The function of artistic expression prior to written records is inferred from evidence of technology and survival strategies. It is also based on the relationship of tools and their function, whether task-related or expressive. Other notes to consider include the<strong> available food sources, the rise of sophisticated culture, and humans’ capacity to shape and manage the environment.</strong></p>
<p>Basic art historical methods can be applied to prehistoric art by comparing works of art, imagery, materials, and techniques to identify patterns. Think a prevalence of transformational anima or human iconography as an example.  Then ethnographic approaches can be used to propose hypotheses such as certain iconography is shamanic in nature.</p>
<p><strong>Cross-cultural comparisons</strong> can help establish wider generalizations. For example, South African, Asian, and indigenous American peoples all participated in rock/cave expressions of a visionary aesthetic In this way, even a small amount of evidence can produce theories. These can be proposed, tested, refined, and potentially rejected by conflicting evidence or new information. This is true as in other periods of art history, as well as other disciplines.</p>
<h4><strong>(1) 2. Great Hall of Bulls</strong></h4>
<p>Prehistoric European.  15,000-13,000 BCE. Prehistoric.</p>
<figure id="attachment_194" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-194" style="width: 942px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-194" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Great-Hall-of-Bulls-2.jpg?resize=942%2C613&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="942" height="613" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Great-Hall-of-Bulls-2.jpg?w=312&amp;ssl=1 312w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Great-Hall-of-Bulls-2.jpg?resize=300%2C195&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 942px) 100vw, 942px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-194" class="wp-caption-text">Great Hall of the Bulls © The Bridgeman Art Library</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Learning Objective: </strong>Prehistoric cave art</p>
<p><strong>Themes: </strong></p>
<p>Animals<br />
Ritual<br />
Site specific<br />
Fertility<br />
Cycle of life<br />
Ceremony<br />
Changing Interpretations</p>
<p>The Caves of Lascaux, in <strong>Lascaux, France</strong>, are some of the most famous in the world. Inside, through a series if tight passageways, that opens up into a space that can hold 50 people is famous <strong><em>Great Hall of Bulls </em>rock painting</strong> is located. The cave made of white calcite, with a non-porous roof, provided the perfect canvass for drawing and painting, while keeping the work dry.</p>
<p><em>The Great Hall of Bulls</em> work measures <strong>11 feet and six inches</strong> long. Made with <strong>charcoal and ochre</strong> that could be mixed into painting materials, the work depicts horses, deer, bison, elks, lions, birds. and people.</p>
<p>The reason for the creation of the work is unknown. Some see it as a narrative of a story. Others think it is a ritual design, honoring animals, to ensure a successful hunt.</p>
<p>The Caves of Lascaux, in one of about 350 groups, found mostly in Southern France and Northern Spain. Neanderthals, named after the valley, where their bones were found, in Neander Valley, Germany and Homo Sapiens (modern humans today) lived in the region for 30, 000 years.</p>
<h4><strong>(1) 8. <em>Stonehenge.</em></strong></h4>
<p>Prehistoric Europe. 2,500-1,600 BCE. Wiltshire, UK. Prehistoric.</p>
<figure id="attachment_191" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-191" style="width: 800px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-191" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Stonehenge-1.jpg?resize=800%2C849&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="800" height="849" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-191" class="wp-caption-text">Stonehenge<br />© Last Refuge/Robert Harding World Imagery/Corbis</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Learning Objective: </strong>Prehistoric European architecture</p>
<p><strong>Themes:</strong></p>
<p>Religion<br />
Architecture<br />
Site-specific<br />
Ritual<br />
Community<br />
Nature<br />
Fertility</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-868" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Map-of-Stonehnege.jpg?resize=657%2C298&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="657" height="298" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Map-of-Stonehnege.jpg?w=657&amp;ssl=1 657w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Map-of-Stonehnege.jpg?resize=300%2C136&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 657px) 100vw, 657px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p>The mysterious <strong>Stonehenge</strong>, in <strong>Wiltshire, United Kingdom</strong> has caused much speculation.  Resting on a large plain the <strong>circle</strong> measures <strong>320 feet in diameter</strong>. The <strong>sandstone slabs</strong> are <strong>30 feet tall</strong>.  These stones came from a local quarry.</p>
<p>The inner Bluestones have been traced to Preseli Hills, in Wales, 200 miles away! The Preseli Dolerite (Bluestone) is a medium grain heavy rock that is even harder than granite.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-866" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Diagrrrrrram-of-Stonehenge.jpg?resize=735%2C542&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="735" height="542" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Diagrrrrrram-of-Stonehenge.jpg?w=735&amp;ssl=1 735w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Diagrrrrrram-of-Stonehenge.jpg?resize=300%2C221&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 735px) 100vw, 735px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<h5><strong>Function</strong></h5>
<p>Historians agree that <strong>Stonehenge </strong>was once a burial ground for at least part of its history. It was also a ceremonial site and site for religious pilgrimage.</p>
<p>Human remains and bones found show signs of illness and injury. This had led to the belief that the site was considered a destination for healing.</p>
<p>In ancient times stones were considered magical. According to Welsh legends, the Preseli Bluestone possesses healing properties.</p>
<p>Is that why these stones were included in the <strong>Stonehenge</strong> sit?</p>
<figure id="attachment_192" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-192" style="width: 750px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-192" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Stonehenge-2.jpg?resize=750%2C239&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="750" height="239" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Stonehenge-2.jpg?w=392&amp;ssl=1 392w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Stonehenge-2.jpg?resize=300%2C96&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-192" class="wp-caption-text">Stonehenge<br />© Luca da Ros/SOPA/Corbis</figcaption></figure>
<h5><strong>Who Built Stonehenge?</strong></h5>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-869" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Building-Stonehenge.jpg?resize=405%2C450&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="405" height="450" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Building-Stonehenge.jpg?w=405&amp;ssl=1 405w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Building-Stonehenge.jpg?resize=270%2C300&amp;ssl=1 270w" sizes="(max-width: 405px) 100vw, 405px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p>Several tribes built <strong>Stonehenge</strong> over the years. This has been proven by the bones, tool and artifacts located at the site.</p>
<h5><strong>How were the stones raised?</strong></h5>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-865" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Stoneraising.jpg?resize=883%2C474&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="883" height="474" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Stoneraising.jpg?w=883&amp;ssl=1 883w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Stoneraising.jpg?resize=300%2C161&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Stoneraising.jpg?resize=768%2C412&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 883px) 100vw, 883px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p><strong> </strong><strong>Vertical stones</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Large holes were dug with one sloping side.</li>
<li>The stone was slid into the hole.</li>
<li>The stone was then hauled upright with fiber rope.</li>
<li>The hole was packed with rubble.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Horizontal stones</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Timber platforms were used to raise the horizontal lintels into position.</li>
<li>The tenons were adjusted to fit the mortise holes.</li>
<li>The stones were moved into place.</li>
</ol>
<h5><strong> </strong><strong>A UNESCO World Heritage Site</strong></h5>
<p><strong> </strong><strong>Stonehenge</strong> is a UNESCO World Heritage Site. Over 1 million people visit annually.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">32</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Global Prehistory 1.2</title>
		<link>https://medievalarthistory.org/global-prehistory-1-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Medieval Art History]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 20:52:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP ART HISTORY COURSE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Global Prehistory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://medievalarthistory.org/?p=29</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Global Prehistory 30,000- 500 BCE Theme:  “Cave Conjecture” This theme addresses the “site” caves of much Paleolithic Art as well &#8230; <span class="more-button"><a href="https://medievalarthistory.org/global-prehistory-1-2/" class="more-link">Continue Reading<span class="screen-reader-text">Global Prehistory 1.2</span></a></span>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2><strong>Global Prehistory</strong></h2>
<h3>30,000- 500 BCE</h3>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-179" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Running-horned-woman.jpg?resize=800%2C948&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="800" height="948" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<h3><strong>Theme:  “Cave Conjecture”</strong></h3>
<p>This theme addresses the “site” caves of much Paleolithic Art as well as the lack of documentation.  Therefore, much of this chapter is comprised of conjecture.</p>
<h4>1.2 <strong>Materials, Process and Techniques in Prehistoric Art</strong></h4>
<h5><strong>The Influence of Africa and Asia</strong></h5>
<p>The first instances of important artistic media, approaches, and values occurred on different continents, with Africa and Asia preceding and influencing other areas as the human population spread.</p>
<p>People established many kinds of artistic media. Some of these were the first fired <strong>ceramics</strong> and <strong>painting</strong>, as well as <strong>incised graphic designs</strong>, primarily on rock surfaces. <strong>Sculpture</strong> featured female forms and animal figurines. <strong>Architecture </strong>included stone megalithic installations.</p>
<h5><strong>The First Art</strong></h5>
<p><strong> </strong>Beginning approximately 77,000 years ago, the first “art” was created in the form of rock paintings and carved natural materials.  These were <strong>two-dimensional</strong> creations of <strong>geometric patterns</strong> and <strong>human and animal</strong> lifeforms. <strong>Three-dimensional</strong> forms included <strong>sculpture, large scale objects, and monuments</strong>. Environments were assembled and/or constructed.</p>
<h5><strong>West, Central and South East Asian Communities</strong></h5>
<p><strong> </strong>Humans established Paleolithic communities in West, Central, South East Asia, and East Asia between 70,000 and 40, 000 BCE.  In prehistoric China, the ritual of making <strong>jade objects</strong>, started a 5000-year tradition of working with this precious medium.  The semi-precious stone is soft but durable. These works had a spiritual symbolism, as they were often buried with the people who owned them.</p>
<p><strong>Ritual, tomb, and memorializing arts</strong> are found across Neolithic Asia, including impressive funerary steles from Saudi Arabia and Yemen.</p>
<p>Asia’s greatest contribution to early world art is in <strong>ceramic</strong> technology, with some of the earliest pieces dating to 10,500 BCE produced by the Jomon culture in Japan.  Even earlier pottery continues to be found, particularly in China. Ceramics were also produced in Iran beginning in the eighth millennium BCE, and refined vessel forms arose from the adoption of the potter’s wheel in the fourth millennium BCE.</p>
<h5><strong>The Migration from Asia</strong></h5>
<p><strong> </strong>In the Pacific region, migrations from Asia, approximately  45,000 years ago, were possible because of lowered sea levels and the existence of land bridges. The earliest created objects have been dated to about 8000 years ago. The Lapita peoples, who moved eastward from Melanesia to Polynesia beginning about 4000 years ago, created pottery with incised geometric designs that appear across the region in multiple media today.</p>
<h5><strong>Artistic Statements</strong></h5>
<p><strong> </strong>Paleolithic and Neolithic Europe’s artistic statements were made in small <strong>human figural sculptures</strong> (central Europe), <strong>cave paintings</strong> (France and Spain), and <strong>outdoor-monumental stone assemblages</strong> (British Isles). These provide glimpses into the beginnings of ritual life in 15,000 BCE.</p>
<p>People tried to influence and integrate with the natural cycles of the cosmos and promote both  human and animal fertility. These works establish the dynamic interplay of naturalism and abstraction found throughout art’s history.</p>
<h5><strong>American Continent Art</strong></h5>
<p>On the American continent, from the Arctic to Tierra del Fuego, indigenous peoples who had recently migrated from Asia, before 10,000 BCE, made <strong>sculptural works, with animals and sacred humans</strong>, as main subject matter.  These were made from <strong>animal bone</strong> and later from <strong>clay.</strong></p>
<p>Similar to European- expressions, ancient American art adapts animal images to the natural contours of the chosen materials and also features fertile females. Many <strong>female figurines</strong> may also display unusual or supernatural characteristics. This  suggests the importance of shamanic religion, brought from Asia, very early in human history.</p>
<p><strong style="color: #000000; font-size: 1.75rem;">(1) 3.<em> Camelid sacrum</em></strong></p>
<p>Prehistoric American (Mexico). 14,000 – 7000 BCE. Prehistoric.</p>
<figure id="attachment_184" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-184" style="width: 500px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-184" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Camelis-Sacrum.jpg?resize=500%2C356&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="500" height="356" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Camelis-Sacrum.jpg?w=323&amp;ssl=1 323w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Camelis-Sacrum.jpg?resize=300%2C214&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-184" class="wp-caption-text">Camelid sacrum<br />Photo © Jorge Pérez de Lara</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Learning Objective: </strong>Prehistoric Mesoamerican fertility object</p>
<p><strong>Themes:</strong></p>
<p>Animals<br />
Ritual<br />
Fertility<br />
Cycle of life<br />
Materials with significance<br />
<strong> </strong></p>
<p>This work of art,<strong><em> Camelid sacrum</em></strong> resembling the face of a canine dog is carved <strong>bone</strong> from the sacrum of a camelid. It was discovered in <strong>Tequixquiac, central Mexico.</strong></p>
<h5><strong>What is a Camelid?</strong></h5>
<p>A <strong>camelid</strong> or palaeloma was a type of horse during prehistoric times that is now extinct.</p>
<h5><strong>What is a Sacrum? </strong></h5>
<p>A sacrum in the <strong>triangular bone in the lower back</strong>. The bone sits between the two hips of the pelvis. In Latin, sacrum means sacred bone.</p>
<h5><strong>Why this was Made?</strong></h5>
<p>This bone was later associated with sacred rituals such as fertility, the cycle of life and burials. Men carried this bone with them when travelling and hunting.</p>
<h5><strong>In Detail</strong></h5>
<p>The symmetry of the bone was used to create a canine work with a three-dimensional impression. The roughness of the bone provides natural texture. Notice the details of the nostrils, mouth, and ears.</p>
<h5><strong>The Importance of Dogs</strong></h5>
<p><strong> </strong>As the first domesticated animal in prehistoric society, dogs played an important role in life.</p>
<h5><strong>Discovery</strong></h5>
<p><em>Camelid Sacrum</em> was discovered completely by accident in 1870, in the Tequixquiac, in the Valley of Mexico. Today this area is part of Mexico city.  This area once held several lakes. The engineer draining the lakes, to build the community found the artwork 40 feet below.</p>
<h4><strong>(1)4<em>. Running Horned Woman</em></strong></h4>
<p>Prehistoric African (Algerian). 6,000- 4000 BCE. Prehistoric</p>
<figure id="attachment_179" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-179" style="width: 500px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-179" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Running-horned-woman.jpg?resize=500%2C593&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="500" height="593" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-179" class="wp-caption-text">Running horned woman<br />© The Granger Collection, New York</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Learning Objective: </strong>Prehistoric African Rock Painting</p>
<p><strong>Theme:</strong></p>
<p>Ritual<br />
Deities<br />
Masks<br />
Stylized bodies<br />
Ceremony<br />
Fertility</p>
<p>Initially named <em>The Horned Goddess</em>, this work of art entitled, <strong><em>Running Horned Woman</em></strong><em>, </em>using <strong>pigment on rock</strong>. Measuring <strong>20 by 9 feet</strong> it is located in the Sahara desert, in the region of Tassili A’Ajjer, <strong>Algeria.</strong></p>
<h5><strong>The Hidden Works</strong></h5>
<p>The landscape of high pillared, smooth rocks, and thin passageways, created the perfect backdrop for both painting and securely storing this work.</p>
<h5><strong>The Details</strong></h5>
<p>The focus is on the large running woman in the foreground, drawn in a naturalistic way. Some of the smaller figures behind her are painted in abstract. She is clearly the subject matter. The careful composition of the woman’s body is in full view.</p>
<h5><strong>Not Your Average Woman</strong></h5>
<p>What makes her image especially notable is the way she is adorned. <strong>Armlets encircle her forearms and guarder wrap her thighs.</strong> All are delicately fringed. Her face is in profile. She is wearing <strong>horns on her head</strong>, which are outward facing. Look closely and you will see she is also <strong>decorated in body paint</strong>.</p>
<p>All of this suggests the scene <strong>represents ceremony, ritual, or rites of passage</strong>. Yet scholars agree, this is not an ordinary woman, depicted in this prehistoric African rock painting.</p>
<h5><strong>Symbolism</strong></h5>
<p>Between the horns, you can view the grains falling from wheat in the distance. <strong>What do you think this symbolizes?</strong></p>
<h5><strong>Discovery</strong></h5>
<p>The Prehistoric African rock painting was discovered high in the canyons by a camel corps officer named Lieutenant Brenans of the French Foreign Legion.  Between 1933 and 1940, he made numerous sketches and notes to detail what he found. These were donated to the Bardo Museum, in Algiers.</p>
<p>Soon French born archaeologist Henri Lhote went to the region and by 1956 assembled a team to study and map the art.  The rock art found here remain the richest concentration of this medium worldwide.</p>
<h4><strong>(1)5.<em> Beaker with Ibex Motif </em></strong></h4>
<p>Prehistoric Middle Eastern (Iran). 4200- 3500 BCE. Prehistoric.</p>
<figure id="attachment_185" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-185" style="width: 484px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-185" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Beaker-with-Ibex.jpg?resize=484%2C751&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="484" height="751" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Beaker-with-Ibex.jpg?w=268&amp;ssl=1 268w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Beaker-with-Ibex.jpg?resize=193%2C300&amp;ssl=1 193w" sizes="(max-width: 484px) 100vw, 484px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-185" class="wp-caption-text">Beaker with ibex motifs<br />© RMN-Grand Palais/Art Resource, NY</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Learning Objective: </strong>Prehistoric Middle Eastern utilitarian object</p>
<p><strong>Themes:</strong></p>
<p>Animals<br />
Utilitarian<br />
Funerary<br />
Ceramics<br />
Status<br />
<strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Beaker with Ibex Motif</em></strong> is a prehistoric Middle Eastern vessel, found in Susa, which today is <strong>Iran. </strong>The beaker measures <strong>1 foot in height</strong> and is made of <strong>terra cotta</strong> that has been <strong>painted</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Animals and motifs</strong> were popular design elements. This beaker is one such beautiful example.</p>
<p>The animals here are all <strong>stylized and viewed in profile</strong>.</p>
<h5><strong>The Painted Elements</strong></h5>
<p>In the centre is a bearded ibex, or mountain goat, composed of two elongated rectangles. This animal symbolized prosperity. The horns dramatically reach back and encircle a symbol that looks like a modern-day baseball.</p>
<p>Above this a series of <strong>dogs</strong>, with stretched bodies that suggest movement. This accentuates the cylindrical shape of the vessel. Dogs were a symbol of protection against threat. Along the entire rim are depictions of <strong>wading birds,</strong> or cranes, with necks as long a giraffe. In opposition, the birds draw attention to the verticality of the vessel.</p>
<h5><strong>Craftmanship and Importance</strong></h5>
<p><strong> </strong>During the Neolithic period, the crafts people of this area were known for their <strong>kiln-fired yellow ceramics</strong> <strong>painted with a flat brown glaze.</strong> It is thought that a slow potter’s wheel was used in creating these works.</p>
<p>It was unearthed near burial tombs, built by the people of Susa. It is important to note that this was not unearthed with human remain, but in an area hundreds of baskets, bowls, and metallic items. <strong><em>Why do you think the people of Susa buried these objects near their burial tombs?</em></strong></p>
<h4><strong>(1) 7. </strong><strong><em>Jade cong</em></strong></h4>
<p>Prehistoric Chinese. 3300-2200 BCE. Prehistoric</p>
<figure id="attachment_186" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-186" style="width: 500px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-186" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Jade-cong.jpg?resize=500%2C366&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="500" height="366" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Jade-cong.jpg?w=325&amp;ssl=1 325w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Jade-cong.jpg?resize=300%2C220&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-186" class="wp-caption-text">Jade cong<br />© Asian Art &amp; Archaeology, Inc./Corbis</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Learning Objective</strong>: Prehistoric Chinese funerary object</p>
<p><strong>Themes</strong>:</p>
<p>Funerary<br />
Materials with significance<br />
Ritual<br />
Status<br />
Duality<br />
Deities<br />
Ancestors</p>
<p><strong>Jade cong</strong> was found in Liangzhu, China. Archaeologists have unearthed supreme examples of congs, created by the Liangzhu people, in royal tombs, palaces, and workshops.  Due to its varied colors and textures,  jade is the material most highly prized throughout Chinese history.</p>
<h5><strong>What is a Cong?</strong></h5>
<p>A cong is a tubular object with a circular hole cut into it in the middle like a cross section.</p>
<h5><strong>A Closer Look</strong></h5>
<p>At each corner of the Jade cong, there is a face patterned, with circular eyes and a slit-like mouth. These images could be deities or ancestral spirits.   The faces are rather abstract, but suggestive indicating a man-like figure or a personified beast.</p>
<p>The viewer focuses on the cylindrical void circular shape within the prism. The visual effect creates equilibrium. It is achieved by the symmetry of the corner face carvings, the concentric circles pattern, the perfect balance given by its equal top and base, by the rather uniform whitish jade color and its polished smoothness.</p>
<p>The theme of this artwork might be Individual and Society because the congs were a status symbol for the deceased. It could also represent Knowledge and Belief due to the symbolism of the carved faces. It might also have as sub-theme of Life Cycles because the height of the cong might measure the generations of the clan and it might be the predecessor of the ancestral tablet.</p>
<h5><strong>What was the Function of a Cong?</strong></h5>
<p>Congs had funeral functions, but what specifically is not known. Congs were placed in the tombs of the wealthy and sometimes they were the only artifact placed there. Surely this means it was an important piece.</p>
<p>One existing theory is that it represented details about the clan.  The layers of the cong could have signified the age and number of generations of the clan.</p>
<p>In this case, a tall cong would mean an old clan, while a short one would be a new clan. More congs in a grave, might mean the deceased was the head of more than one clan. The cong might be the predecessor of the ancestral tablet. This was placed in the ancestral temple, representing thus the spirit of the ancestors and a cosmic pillar connecting earth and heavens.</p>
<h5><strong>Background</strong></h5>
<p>The cong belongs to the <strong>Neolithic Period</strong> 2500 B.C.E Liangzhu culture, Jiangsu province of China, located south of the Yangzi River. The Liangzhu culture was characterized by a series of prosperous city-states, cultivated rice, and domesticated pigs. With a stable food supply the society could afford the high specialization of its jade carvers.</p>
<p>The Liangzhu society was hierarchal as the jade congs could only be found in elite tombs. The periods of relative calm between floodings must have been long because the cong is a large piece of jade. Jade’s particularity is that it can only be sanded out. It cannot be simply cut. It must be polished, so the artisans needed time and resources to produce it.</p>
<p><strong>The cong associates jade with divinity and power.</strong>  This association continued until the late Song Dynasty (960-1279 CE) during which a deity was called the Jade Emperor.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h4><strong>(1)6. </strong><em> </em><strong>Anthropomorphic stele</strong></h4>
<p>Prehistoric Middle Eastern. 4,000 BCE. Prehistoric</p>
<figure id="attachment_187" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-187" style="width: 500px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-187" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Antropomorphic-stele.jpg?resize=500%2C752&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="500" height="752" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Antropomorphic-stele.jpg?w=276&amp;ssl=1 276w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Antropomorphic-stele.jpg?resize=200%2C300&amp;ssl=1 200w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-187" class="wp-caption-text">Anthropomorphic stele<br />© Album/Art Resource, NY</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Learning objective<em>: </em></strong>Prehistoric Middle Eastern funerary object</p>
<p><strong>Themes: </strong></p>
<p>Funerary<br />
Stylized bodies<br />
Deities<br />
Guardian<br />
Ancestors<br />
<strong><em> </em></strong></p>
<p><strong>Anthropomorphic stele</strong> measuring <strong>3 feet tall</strong>, found in the <strong>Arabian Peninsula</strong> is made of <strong>sandstone</strong>. Both sides of this piece are sculpted.</p>
<h5><strong>What is a Stele? </strong></h5>
<p>A stele is a stone marker or monument that is often inscribed with relief or text. The plural word for stele is stelae.</p>
<h5><strong>A Closer Look</strong></h5>
<p>The focus is on the front of the work and its<strong> anthropomorphic, or human like qualities.  </strong>The head rests squarely on the shoulders. The eyes are created in <strong>relief</strong>, with a flattened nose. There are two cords around the body, and a dagger is attached to a belt. A decorative necklace hangs at the neck.</p>
<p>What makes this funerary object so extraordinary is that the <strong>minimalistic style</strong> manages to be very expressive.</p>
<h4><strong>(1) 11.<em> Terra Cotta Fragments</em></strong></h4>
<p><em>Prehistoric Oceania (Lapita). 1000 BCE. Prehistoric</em></p>
<figure id="attachment_188" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-188" style="width: 500px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-188" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Terra-cotta-fragments.jpg?resize=500%2C460&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="500" height="460" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Terra-cotta-fragments.jpg?w=322&amp;ssl=1 322w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Terra-cotta-fragments.jpg?resize=300%2C276&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-188" class="wp-caption-text">Terra cotta fragment<br />Courtesy of the Anthropology Photographic Archive, Department of<br />Anthropology, The University of Auckland</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Learning Objective: </strong>Prehistoric Oceanic utilitarian object</p>
<p><strong>Themes: </strong></p>
<p>Utilitarian<br />
Status</p>
<p>These <strong>Terra Cotta Fragments</strong> were found at <strong>Solomon Islands</strong>. The Lapita people who created these works were travellers, as can be concluded by the various locations that the pottery pieces were found.  beyond Oceania. This also includes South East Asia, Micronesia, Melanesia, central Pacific, and Polynesia.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-863" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Map-wher-Terra-Cotta-Pieces-were-Found.png?resize=353%2C386&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="353" height="386" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Map-wher-Terra-Cotta-Pieces-were-Found.png?w=353&amp;ssl=1 353w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Map-wher-Terra-Cotta-Pieces-were-Found.png?resize=274%2C300&amp;ssl=1 274w" sizes="(max-width: 353px) 100vw, 353px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<h5><strong><em> </em></strong><strong><em>Form and Function</em></strong></h5>
<p>Historians have determined that these pieces were shaped by hand. Then, <strong>incised</strong> or even stamped with repeating geometric patterns. What is also interesting to note is that the clay was mixed with sand from a specific region, ensuring that the materials were brought in from different locations, probably in the form of trade. The sand strengthened the vessels during the firing stage, keeping the objects from expanding and cracking when fired.</p>
<p>Most objects were bowls. This means they had a <strong>utilitarian function</strong>. Some had flat bottoms. While others were presented on raised feet.</p>
<h5>UP NEXT:</h5>
<p><strong>Global Prehistoric History  </strong></p>
<p><strong>30,000- 500 BCE</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://medievalarthistory.org/global-prehistory-1-3/">Topic 1.3  Theories and Interpretations of Prehistoric Art</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">29</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Global Prehistory 1.1</title>
		<link>https://medievalarthistory.org/global-prehistory-1-1/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Medieval Art History]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 15:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP ART HISTORY COURSE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Global Prehistory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://medievalarthistory.org/?p=22</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Global Prehistory 30,000 BCE to 5000 BCE Theme:  “Cave Conjecture” This theme addresses the “site” caves of much Paleolithic Art &#8230; <span class="more-button"><a href="https://medievalarthistory.org/global-prehistory-1-1/" class="more-link">Continue Reading<span class="screen-reader-text">Global Prehistory 1.1</span></a></span>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2><strong>Global Prehistory</strong></h2>
<h3><strong style="font-size: 2.5rem;">30,000 BCE to 5000 BCE</strong></h3>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-179" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Running-horned-woman.jpg?resize=800%2C948&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="800" height="948" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<h3><strong>Theme:  “Cave Conjecture”</strong></h3>
<p>This theme addresses the “site” caves of much Paleolithic Art as well as the lack of documentation.  Therefore, much of this chapter is comprised of conjecture.</p>
<h5><strong>Historical Context</strong></h5>
<ul>
<li>Prehistory includes all of human existence before emergence of writing.</li>
<li>Paleolithic Art /Age: 40,000 BCE – 8000 BCE
<ul>
<li>Characterized by hunter-gathering</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Neolithic Art / Age: 8000 BCE – 3000 BCE
<ul>
<li style="list-style-type: none;">
<ul>
<li>Characterized by agriculture, civilization, occupations</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h5><strong>Artistic Innovations</strong></h5>
<ul>
<li>Earliest surviving works of art are comprised of cave paintings and portable sculptures of humans and animals.
<ul>
<li>Conjecture as to why these works were made or what they meant.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Years following 30,000 BCE saw a powerful outburst of creativity.</li>
<li>Enlarged sexual organs prominent in sculptures; reveal importance of reproduction</li>
<li>Cave paintings: animals are realistic while humans are stick figures<strong style="font-size: 1.0625rem;"> </strong></li>
</ul>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-862" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Rocks.jpg?resize=525%2C265&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="525" height="265" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Rocks.jpg?w=525&amp;ssl=1 525w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Rocks.jpg?resize=300%2C151&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 525px) 100vw, 525px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<h4><strong>1.1 Cultural Influences on Prehistoric Art</strong></h4>
<p>Human expression existed across the globe before the written record. Although prehistoric Europe has been the focus of many introductions to the history of art, early art is found worldwide. It shares certain features, particularly in concern with the natural world and humankind’s place within it.</p>
<h5><strong>Before the Written Record</strong></h5>
<p>The analysis and interpretations of art from this period are especially important, as little-to-no written evidence exists for such early works. Art historians develop theories, in collaboration with social and physical scientists, to understand art historical developments.</p>
<h5><strong>Climate and Environment</strong></h5>
<p>Periods before the written record are often defined in terms of geological eras or major shifts in climate and environment. Human behavior and expression were influenced by the changing environments in which they lived.  A glacial period produced European ice ages. Saharan agricultural grassland became desert. Tectonic shifts, in southeast Asia, created land bridges between the continent and the now-islands of the Pacific, south of the equator.</p>
<h5><strong>Macrocosmic and Micro Cosmic Awareness</strong></h5>
<p>In many world regions, including those not in direct contact with one another, art shows humans’ awareness of fundamental, stable phenomena.  Astronomical cycles, such as equinoxes and solstices have frequently been a factor in the influence of art from a macrocosmic perspective.  On a smaller scope, microcosmic influences, including the exploitation of permanent materials available in local environments, such as <strong>stone</strong>, <strong>hardened</strong> <strong>clay</strong>, and <strong>jade</strong>, are all determining factors in early creation.</p>
<h5><strong>Defining the Stone Ages</strong></h5>
<p>The periods of global prehistory are known as lithic or stone ages. These include Paleolithic (“Old Stone Age”), Mesolithic (“Middle Stone Age”), and Neolithic (“New Stone Age”). Each period brought with it culture depicted in art.</p>
<h5><strong>Historical Context</strong><strong> </strong></h5>
<ul>
<li><strong>Paleolithic Period or Old Stone Age</strong> (40,000 BCE–10,000 BCE)</li>
<li><strong>Mesolithic Period or Middle Stone Age</strong> (10,000 BCE–8,000 BCE)</li>
<li><strong>Neolithic Period or New Stone Age</strong> (8,000 BCE–3,000 BCE)</li>
</ul>
<h5><strong>Hunter-Gatherers Survival and Art (Paleolithic Period/ Old Stone Age)</strong></h5>
<p><strong>40,000 BCE–10,000 BCE</strong></p>
<p>Globally, the earliest peoples were small groups of hunter-gatherers, whose paramount concern was sheer survival. This resulted in the creation of <strong>practical objects</strong>. Stone tools were fashioned and used to <strong>cut, scrape, carve</strong> and <strong>kill</strong>.</p>
<p>From earliest times, these practical tools were accompanied by objects of unknown purpose—<strong>ritual and symbolic works</strong>, perhaps intended to encourage the availability of flora and fauna food sources. These works included large cave drawings, but also, small moveable, primitive sculpture art. Made from <strong>clay, bone, ivory, </strong>and <strong>stone,</strong> a popular theme during this time was <strong>Venus art</strong>, or figurines <strong>representing female fertility</strong>.</p>
<h5><strong>Art As A Community (Mesolithic Period/ Middle Stone Age)</strong></h5>
<p><strong>10,000 BCE–8,000 BCE</strong></p>
<p>During this period, people began to settle in communities. This resulted in more <strong>human depictions</strong> in artworks. As humans began to find their home, domesticated pets were added, such as the dog. Sculpture became more sophisticated, and clay was now finished by firing.</p>
<h5><strong>Art Depicting Stone Age Life (Neolithic Period/New Stone Age)</strong></h5>
<p><strong>8,000 BCE–3,000 BCE</strong></p>
<p>During the Neolithic period society began to advance. The earliest forms of architecture emerged. Farming was a way of life now, with the domestication of plants and farm animals.</p>
<p>Art making was associated with activities such as food production. Think <strong>hunting, gathering, agriculture</strong>, and <strong>animal husbandry</strong>. It also illustrated patterns of behavior, such as <strong>settlement</strong>, demonstration of <strong>status</strong>, and <strong>burial</strong>. For example, places of gathering or settlement and/or objects found in such places may be painted and/or incised with imagery related to their use.</p>
<p>Sophisticated <strong>weaving </strong>was found in fabric for clothing. Art was increasingly stylized and continued to show more craftsmanship.</p>
<h4><strong>(1) 1.<em> Apollo 11 Stones</em></strong></h4>
<p>Prehistoric African (Namibia). 25, 500 BCE to 25, 300 BCE. Prehistoric</p>
<figure id="attachment_175" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-175" style="width: 500px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-175" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Apollo-11-Stones.jpg?resize=500%2C382&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="500" height="382" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-175" class="wp-caption-text">Apollo 11 stones<br />© Human Origins Program, Smithsonian Institution</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Learning Objective: </strong>Earliest example of representation</p>
<p><strong>Themes:</strong></p>
<p>Animals<br />
Ritual<br />
Fertility<br />
Cycle of life</p>
<p>This work, created with <strong>charcoal on stone</strong>, entitled <strong><em>Apollo 11 Stones</em></strong><em>, </em>are cave stones discovered in <strong>Namibia, Africa, in 1969</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>What do you think this piece might have been used for?</strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Apollo</em> <em>11 Stones</em></strong> depicts an animal which is thought to be a <strong>Thrianthrope</strong>, or a creature that in mythology can shape shift. It is <strong>anthropomorphic</strong>, with characteristics of the human form, although the form itself is not human. In this case the hind legs are human, while front legs are feline in nature. The work has a <strong>twisted perspective</strong>, in which the viewer can see the combined side and front view of the creature. The thin legs and a body without much detail, give it the visual effect of agility.</p>
<h5><strong>Historical Background</strong></h5>
<p>This year coincides with the landing on the moon of the Apollo 11, hence the name. Several other tablets depicting animals were found at the same time. Although this work is small enough to be carried in one hand, the function of the pieces is unknown.</p>
<h4><strong>(1) 9. The Ambum Stone</strong></h4>
<p>Prehistoric Oceania. 1500 BCE</p>
<figure id="attachment_176" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-176" style="width: 500px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-176" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Ambum-Stone.jpg?resize=500%2C597&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="500" height="597" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Ambum-Stone.jpg?w=320&amp;ssl=1 320w, https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Ambum-Stone.jpg?resize=251%2C300&amp;ssl=1 251w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-176" class="wp-caption-text">The Ambum stone<br />© National Gallery of Australia, Canberra</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Learning Objective: </strong>Prehistoric Oceanic ritual object</p>
<p><strong>Themes: </strong></p>
<p>Animals<br />
Ritual<br />
Fertility<br />
Cycle of life<br />
Utilitarian</p>
<p><strong><em>The Ambum Stone</em></strong><em>, </em>was found in Ambum Valley, Enga Province of <strong>Papua, New Guinea</strong>. The <strong>8-inch-tall</strong> piece is a decorative, but utilitarian object, made from <strong>greywacke</strong>, a heavy stone.</p>
<h5><strong>An Ancient Pestle</strong></h5>
<p>The curved head and long nose provided a handle to hold.  The body would have been used to crush or grind food, in a mortar or bowl.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-177" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Ambum-Stone-Close-Up.jpg?resize=301%2C194&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="301" height="194" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<p>Historians believe the work represents an <strong>anteater</strong>.</p>
<p>What do you think this animal is?</p>
<h5><strong> </strong><strong>A Rare Find</strong></h5>
<p><strong><em>The Ambum Stone</em></strong>, is considered most extraordinary, because of the attention to detail.  Look at the animal’s eyes, nose and ears carved in relief and depicted in a stylized manner.</p>
<h5><strong>More Objects Uncovered</strong></h5>
<p>Over a dozen similar tools have been found in the region, with human or bird heads, as well as full birds in flight.</p>
<h4><strong>(1) 9. Tlatilco female figurine</strong></h4>
<p>Prehistoric American (Mexico). 1200-900 BCE. Prehistoric</p>
<figure id="attachment_180" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-180" style="width: 500px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-180" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Tlatilco-female-figurine.jpg?resize=500%2C653&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="500" height="653" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-180" class="wp-caption-text">Tlatilco female figurine<br />© Princeton University Art Museum/Art Resource, NY</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Learning Objective</strong>: Prehistoric Mesoamerican funerary object</p>
<p><strong>Themes:</strong></p>
<p>Stylized bodies<br />
Ritual<br />
Funerary<br />
Duality<br />
Death<br />
Fertility</p>
<p>This prehistoric American <strong>(Mexican)</strong> <strong>ceramic</strong> work is a small free-standing figure of a woman, <strong>just four inches high</strong>. Craftsmanship in the elaborate and decorative hairstyle shows great technique. Many sculptures from this time depict similar traits, as well as the use of body paint on female figurative art. This suggests this style of adornment was highly valued in Tlatilco society.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-181" src="https://i0.wp.com/medievalarthistory.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Tlatilco-feamle-close-up.jpg?resize=260%2C171&#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="260" height="171" data-recalc-dims="1" /></p>
<h5><strong>Historical Context</strong></h5>
<p>The <strong>Tlatilco female figurine</strong> is a prime example of the kinds of sculptural works uncovered in Central Mexico. Before the Aztecs dominated this land, the Tlatilco people flourished at least 3000 years prior. In the 20<sup>th</sup> century, clay mining, for the use of making bricks, uncovered graves, in which such works were found.</p>
<h4><strong>NEXT UP: </strong></h4>
<p><strong>Global Prehistoric History  </strong><br />
<strong>30,000- 500 BCE</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://medievalarthistory.org/global-prehistory-1-2/">1.2 Materials, Process and Techniques in Prehistoric Art</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">22</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
